<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TU Computer Science and Engineering</title>
    <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TU Computer Science and Engineering</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 16:12:15 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://timtheswan.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Jon Denning</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/denning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/denning/</guid>
      <description>Bio In fall 2014, I started as an assistant professor teaching computer graphics and core Computer Science courses. I find graphics fascinating because it creatively combines many disciplines—physics, math, data structures, and art—and produces images that are simple, yet awe-inspiring and rich with details.
The past few years have been a whirlwind of excitement for and blessings on my family, and looking back it’s obvious that God has led us to where we are now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Stefan Brandle</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/brandle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/brandle/</guid>
      <description>Bio What do I say? Great literature is supposed to have a catchy first line. Moby Dick begins, “Call me Ishmael.” But I’m not sure that I’m up to great literature. And my name’s not Ishmael. Should I write something profound? Something frivolous? What does one say about oneself in this sort of situation?
I wish to serve God in all aspects of my life. That commission includes my professional field and my job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Art White</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/white/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:51:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/white/</guid>
      <description>Bio I teach because I believe the Lord has called me to teaching and I deeply enjoy teaching and time spent with young people. Seeing students become excited about the field of computing is extremely gratifying. I love experiencing the “aha!” moments as students comprehend new concepts in computer science. I enjoy working with students to help them develop their analysis, design, programming, and debugging skills. I find these skills apply not only to programming, but also to other areas of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Jonathan Geisler</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/geisler/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/geisler/</guid>
      <description>Bio What can I say that’s enlightening? I’m not as funny as Dr. Brandle, so I think I’ll just be plain and tell you a bit about myself.
I’m a Taylor Computer Science and Engineering grad (Dec. ’94), so I’ve been involved in the department since 1991. I took a couple years off to work at Argonne National Laboratory before attending Northwestern University for my PhD. Technically, I’m a Computer Engineer, so I work with the Physics department to make sure that program is up to snuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Tom Nurkkala</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/nurkkala/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/nurkkala/</guid>
      <description>Bio I’m at Taylor because I want to help train and mentor excellent computer scientists and engineers who are also dedicated followers of Christ. In addition, as a member of the Center for Missions Computing, I want to leverage the intellectual horsepower and spiritual maturity of the students at Taylor to help solve practical computing problems for the global mission community.
To accomplish these goals, I plan to employ my educational and industrial experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Dannie Stanley</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/stanley/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/stanley/</guid>
      <description>Bio When I set out to become a professor in 2004, I identified Taylor University specifically as the place that I would like to teach. I did not realize at the time how unlikely it was that I would actually get to work at my first choice (but here I sit). Though I was not a student at Taylor, I grew up in nearby Van Buren and was surrounded by community members involved with Taylor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Jeff Cramer</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/cramer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/cramer/</guid>
      <description>Bio As an elementary education major at Taylor University, I always thought I would someday like to be a professor. I never thought I would return to Taylor via the Computer Science and Engineering department!
After teaching in a public school in Indianapolis for six years, I decided to go back to graduate school. While working on my M.S. degree in Instructional Systems Technology at Indiana University, I realized how much I liked learning about the appropriate uses of technology in an educational setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Ben Roller</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/roller/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/roller/</guid>
      <description>Bio Vital Stats Degrees:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mr. Tim Lehrian</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/lehrian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 14:13:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/lehrian/</guid>
      <description>Bio When I was a little kid, I told my dad I wanted to be an architect just like him. We would go into business together and call it “Lehrian &amp;amp; Father.” Only I didn’t pursue architecture. I did math instead.
My goal was not to work in IT as a career. Then IWU’s IT Dept snagged me shortly after graduation. That launched me into an IT career path that eventually resulted in working as a sysadmin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mr. William Slauson</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/slauson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 14:13:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/slauson/</guid>
      <description>Bio I was born into a family of soldiers, missionaries and physicians. I spent most of my life in a Northern Virginia suburb, but I have traveled extensively.My faith has played a central role in my life. I was saved young and have found purpose and joy in my relationship with Christ.
I have enjoyed technology since my first DOS machine at the age of 5. I also have broad interests in most of the liberal arts, but I especially enjoy mathematics, physics, philosophy and political science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mrs. Lara Horsley</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/horsley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 14:13:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/horsley/</guid>
      <description>Bio I’ve been working as the Program Assistant for the Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) department since fall 2011. For nine years I was the only sister of three older brothers, so I know how to handle anything these guys can throw at me. Prior to working for the CSE department, I worked on the first floor of Nussbaum Science Center as the Program Assistant for the School of Natural &amp;amp; Applied Sciences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Info</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/information/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 10:34:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/information/info/</guid>
      <description>For Prospective Students Looking to find the Computer Science department that&amp;rsquo;s right for you?
 Look at our curriculum
 Check out the course list
 Have your frequently asked questions answered
 See what cool activities our students participate in
 Meet some of our current students  , alumni, or our faculty
 Look at some of our students&amp;rsquo; projects
 Meet Yosef  , your admissions counsellor for students in Applied Sciences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alumni</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/alumni/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 12:52:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/alumni/</guid>
      <description>Zach Alford   Zach Alford teaches math
    Zach Alford graduated from Taylor in 2016 with a Computer Science major, and Mathematics minor.
Zach appreciates how his Taylor education gave him skills integral to future development, both in his field and out. Academically, Zach learned attention for accuracy, cognitive persistence, how to work in groups, and valuable problem-solving skills. In Taylor&amp;rsquo;s liberal arts education, Zach learned how to effectively express himself, both in conversation and in writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Our Students</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/students/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 16:54:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/students/</guid>
      <description>Courtney Masters   Courtney is a Sophomore studying Digital Media
    Courtney Masters is a Sophomore studying Computer Science - Digital Media B.A. She is currently most interested in a career in web development or software engineering after she graduates in 2022.
Courtney heard about Taylor&amp;rsquo;s Computer Science department from her older brother and other friends. &amp;ldquo;I was particularly attracted to the digital media program because it incorporated design and film along with programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018-2019 Posters</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/posters/2018_19_posters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 10:54:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/posters/2018_19_posters/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Year Projects</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/projects/introductory_projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 13:29:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/projects/introductory_projects/</guid>
      <description>Whose AI will win?
   In their first year, Computer Science students will take both COS 120, and COS 121, which teaches students to code from square one. Regardless of the experience students come in with, they will be given the foundational skills necessary code their own AIs (artificial intelligence) to play games, like Checkers, Risk, and Battleships.
COS 120, Introduction to Computational Problem Solving, teaches students essential coding principles, and gives them their first taste solving real world computational problems using Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/information/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 11:39:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/information/links/</guid>
      <description> As a student, you have free access to the complete suite of developer tools by JetBrains. Find out more here.
 To activate Azure for students to get access to a suite of services to help you develop and deploy enterprise-grade web apps, among other things, sign in to your Taylor account here. 
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poster Printing Services</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/information/poster_printing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 11:28:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/information/poster_printing/</guid>
      <description>THIS IS NOT THE TAYLOR PRINT SHOP. We cannot accept the discount coupons/forms that they provide. Please contact the University Press at x85218 or visit them (by the TU Post Office) if you have a coupon and need a poster printed. 
The CSE Dept is happy to provide large format printing for our students. We can print up to 42&amp;rdquo; wide by any length. New for 2017: We are using semi-gloss coated paper, which makes your prints look much nicer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/information/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 10:38:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/information/faq/</guid>
      <description>FAQ  What kind of computer or software will be needed?  Most computers within a decade old will suffice. Students do most of the work on lab computers, where all needed software is already installed. That said, most of the needed software is available for free. Once you get your Taylor email address, you will have access to Microsoft Office, and the entire JetBrains development suite , among other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GameJam</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/gamejam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 15:00:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/gamejam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://gamejam.cse.taylor.edu/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TU CSE GameJam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  is a game jam series hosted every semester by the CSE Department and &lt;a href=&#34;https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/denning&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Jon Denning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and run by students at Taylor University. A game jam is a short, fun, and intense party during which students get together to develop a video game from scratch. Regardless of major or knowledge of programming, all TU students are invited to participate!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Josh Hibschman</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/hibschman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/hibschman/</guid>
      <description>Bio Making a change
Vital Stats Degrees:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Steven Dalcher</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/dalcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/dalcher/</guid>
      <description> Bio Vital Stats Degrees:
Contact </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professor Darci Nurkkala</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/nurkkala_darci/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/nurkkala_darci/</guid>
      <description>Bio Vital Stats Degrees:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems Option</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/information/systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:25:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/information/systems/</guid>
      <description>What is Systems?   What in the world is Accenture selling? The basic answer is “systems.” Accenture’s mission is to help their clients achieve “high performance.”  Accenture, like the Systems curriculum often does
this by helping their clients hone their business
processes or implement new technologies.
   Systems is not a minor in Computer Science. The goal of the Systems curriculum is to help students recognize that the world is filled with systems (like educational, distribution, and manufacturing systems).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abet Accreditation</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/information/abet_accreditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 11:07:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/information/abet_accreditation/</guid>
      <description>Our Engineering &amp;amp; Computer Engineering programs
are ABET-accredited.
   Accreditation The Engineering &amp;amp; Computer Engineering degree programs are accredited by the Engineering Accreditation Commission of ABET (https://www.abet.org). Program Educational Objectives  Prepare our graduates to server others dependably, most importantly their employer, customers, and community. Prepare our graduates to practice technical competence, producing reliable engineering designs. Prepare our graduates to exercise creativity in their work, fostering innovative solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/information/about_us_old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 10:18:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/information/about_us_old/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes alumni Ashley Crutcher designs websites that convince people to buy products,
like guacamole. But sometimes her goal is more serious, like convincing people to follow Jesus.
   At Taylor University, the Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering (CSE) department is more than just a section of the science building. We have our own community on the second floor of the environmentally sustainable Euler Science Complex that flourishes as a learning environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Media BA 4 Year Planner</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/information/digital_media_ba/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 14:39:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/information/digital_media_ba/</guid>
      <description> Digital Media BA Sample 4 Year Plan Please note that these are not official, these plans serve only as general guidelines. Freshman Year 
  Fall   Course # Course Title   Hours    COS 120  Introduction to Computational Problem Solving 4   COS 1__  CSE Orientation 1   IAS 110  Foundations of the Christian Liberal Arts 4   ENG 110  Expository Writing 3   MAT 210  Introductory Statistics 4     J-Term   Course # Course Title   Hours    COS 143 Interactive Web Page Design 3     Spring   Course # Course Title   Hours    COS 121  Foundations of Computer Science 4   BIB 110  Biblical Literature I 3   CAS 110  Public Speaking 3   ART 154  Digital Tools: Photoshop 1   MAT 210  Introductory Statistics 4      Sophomore Year    Fall   Course # Course Title   Hours    COS 120  Introduction to Computational Problem Solving 4   COS 103  CSE Orientation 1   IAS 110  Foundations of the Christian Liberal Arts 4   ENG 110  Expository Writing 3   MAT 210  Introductory Statistics 4     J-Term   Course # Course Title   Hours    COS 143 Interactive Web Page Design 3     Spring   Course # Course Title   Hours    COS 121  Foundations of Computer Science 4   BIB 110  Biblical Literature I 3   CAS 110  Public Speaking 3   ART 154  Digital Tools: Photoshop 1   MAT 210  Introductory Statistics 4      Junior Year    Fall   Course # Course Title   Hours    COS 120  Introduction to Computational Problem Solving 4   COS 1__  CSE Orientation 1   IAS 110  Foundations of the Christian Liberal Arts 4   ENG 110  Expository Writing 3   MAT 210  Introductory Statistics 4     J-Term   Course # Course Title   Hours    COS 143 Interactive Web Page Design 3     Spring   Course # Course Title   Hours    COS 121  Foundations of Computer Science 4   BIB 110  Biblical Literature I 3   CAS 110  Public Speaking 3   ART 154  Digital Tools: Photoshop 1   MAT 210  Introductory Statistics 4      Senior Year    Fall   Course # Course Title   Hours    COS 120  Introduction to Computational Problem Solving 4   COS 1__  CSE Orientation 1   IAS 110  Foundations of the Christian Liberal Arts 4   ENG 110  Expository Writing 3   MAT 210  Introductory Statistics 4     J-Term   Course # Course Title   Hours    COS 143 Interactive Web Page Design 3     Spring   Course # Course Title   Hours    COS 121  Foundations of Computer Science 4   BIB 110  Biblical Literature I 3   CAS 110  Public Speaking 3   ART 154  Digital Tools: Photoshop 1   MAT 210  Introductory Statistics 4      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taylor Satellite (TSAT)</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/projects/tsat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 12:42:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/projects/tsat/</guid>
      <description>Taylor to the skies  TSAT launching from Cape Canaveral (Photo courtesy of NASA.)
   The Taylor Satellite (TSAT) is a student-developed dual Cube-Sat Unit (4 x 4 x 8 inches) nanosatellite participating in NASA’s ELANA-5 (Educational Launch of Nanosatellites). TSAT was selected by NASA in a competitive program with other universities and was the only undergraduate program chosen. TSAT is short for Taylor, Technology, and TEST – Satellite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taylor Sends ThinSat to Space</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/thinsat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 08:18:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/thinsat/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Ellie Tiemens
  Computer science and engineering students made Taylor history with the launch of their nanosatellite. Photo by Ryan Jones
    Taylor University students and faculty recently partnered with NearSpace Launch Inc. to make history in sending nanosatellites to space.
On April 17 at 4:46 p.m., computer science students, engineering students and faculty watched as nearly two years their of hard work was launched into space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big dreams compete with little time at Game Jam 2019</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/gamejam_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 08:18:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/gamejam_2019/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Emily Pawlowski
  The winners of GameJam Spring 2019
    Twenty-four hours is not a lot of time. But for 20 students, it is just enough to create a video game.
Eight teams competed in the 2019 spring Game Jam. They had from April 4 - 6 to find out the theme, design the levels and program a working game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COS Students Make Physical Objects</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/cos_students_make/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 11:03:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/cos_students_make/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Carly Wheeler
  Senior Micah Stewart presents his project for COS 270.
    The Taylor University Computer Science Department is stepping into new territory this semester as students are able to take the class 3D rapid prototyping (COS 270) for the first time.
Taught by engineering project support Steve Dalcher, this pioneer class is diving into an area of computer programming brand new to Taylor academics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alumnus Receives Teaching Fellowship</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/alumnus_recieves_fellowship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 10:55:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/alumnus_recieves_fellowship/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Taylor Budzikowski
  Zach Alford (‘16) is one of the Woodrow Wilson Teaching Fellowship winners this year.
    Zach Alford (&amp;lsquo;16) received the Woodrow Wilson Teaching Fellowship earlier this year.
Alford is one of 24 recipients of the highly competitive fellowship in 2018. The fellowship selects educators who demonstrate impact and a strong background of STEM education in their undergraduate studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truax Creates Audio App for Amazon Alexa</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/truax_creates_audio_app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 10:41:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/truax_creates_audio_app/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Rayce Patterson
  The winners of GameJam Spring 2019
    Senior Caleb Truax III started the company Drift Sounds while still a student at Taylor University.
Truax is a film and computer science student who has worked on projects like the student short films, &amp;ldquo;The Summer of &amp;lsquo;59&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Nuworld,&amp;rdquo; according to his website. However, his entrepreneurial spirit led him and his business partner, Timothy Woten from technology company Sweetwater, to create Drift Sounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CERIAS Security Symposium</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/cerias_symposium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 15:00:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/cerias_symposium/</guid>
      <description>By: Dannie M. Stanley Sat, Apr 7, 2018 Ported from CyberSecurity Site
This week eight students ventured with me to Purdue University in West Lafayette, IN, to attend the 19th annual CERIAS Security Symposium. As a graduate student at Purdue I was heavily involved with CERIAS, so the trip was both highly relevant to our students and a good chance for me to reconnect with cybersecurity colleagues.
Symposium presenters and panelists are cybersecurity experts from academia, industry, and government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taylor Students Build Satellites</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/taylor_students_build_satellites/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 11:16:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/taylor_students_build_satellites/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Hannah Stumpf
  (L to R) Professor Bill Bauson stands with senior Justin Theien, chief engineer for the ThinSat satellite project.
    Taylor University students hope to launch a new ThinSat satellite in October 2018.
The group was first brought together by former Professor Emeritus of Engineering and Physics Hank Voss. Voss was involved in space science at a previous job, and it was there that he encountered a whole field of study called nanosatellites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lockheed Martin Grant Extended for Further Malware Research</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/lockheed_martin_grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 15:30:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/lockheed_martin_grant/</guid>
      <description>Reposted from the Taylor University Site
    Aerospace and defense industry company Lockheed Martin has granted a $75,000 renewal of a grant to the Taylor University Computer Science (CSE) Department as part of a multi-year partnership to create cybersecurity solutions. The grant comes a little more than a year after the preliminary $100,000 grant from Lockheed Martin Advanced Technology Labs for research work done in 2017.
According to Taylor faculty members, a number of Taylor CSE students and faculty worked on the project during the 2017 spring and fall semesters, and also during the summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girls In STEM</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/girls_in_stem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 11:25:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/girls_in_stem/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Hannah Stumpf
  (Photograph provided by Unsplash)
    It all started with TWEET. And no, not the 280-character kind. TWEET stands for Taylor Women Engaging in Engineering and Technology, and those women of Taylor&amp;rsquo;s science, technology, engineering and math (STEM) created a program to get young girls in the community involved with science.
On Tuesday, March 6, one such meeting was held in Euler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity Lecture Asks Big Questions</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/cybersecurity_lecture_asks_big_questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 11:33:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/cybersecurity_lecture_asks_big_questions/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Hannah Stumpf
  The importance of the new cybersecurity major becomes a greater issue as world technology progresses.
    On Feb. 2, Taylor University welcomed Grant Hollis (&amp;lsquo;04), lead research scientist with Lockheed Martin Advanced Technology Laboratories (LM ATL), to speak on current events in cybersecurity and to raise awareness for Taylor&amp;rsquo;s new major.
Hollis worked part-time as a system administrator for Taylor&amp;rsquo;s computer science department.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature Selection for Malware Classification</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/projects/feature_selection_for_malware_classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 11:58:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/projects/feature_selection_for_malware_classification/</guid>
      <description>Feature Selection for Malware Classification    Mitchell Mays Noah Drabinsky Dr. Stefan Brandle Fri, Apr 28, 2017
In applying machine learning to malware identification, different types of features have proven to be successful. These features have also been tested with different kinds of classification methodologies and have had varying degrees of success. Every time a new machine learning methodology is introduced for classifying malware, there is the potential for increasing the overall quality of malware classification in the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Birth of Cybersecurity</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/birth-of-cybersecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 11:41:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/birth-of-cybersecurity/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Annabelle Blair
  A few students in the Software Reverse Engineering and Analysis class, pictured above, prepared for class by spending a day in Washington D.C..
    It&amp;rsquo;s been created and has a list of classes established, but Taylor&amp;rsquo;s cybersecurity major doesn&amp;rsquo;t officially exist-at least, not yet.
Current students will be allowed to enroll in the major when the catalogue comes out in August, and incoming students can declare it now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved User Security Through Graphical Feedback</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/projects/improved_user_security_through_graphical_feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 11:58:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/projects/improved_user_security_through_graphical_feedback/</guid>
      <description>Improved User Security Through Graphical Feedback Justice Juraschek Dannie M. Stanley Wed, Jul 27, 2016
A plethora of methods of being secure are available to end-users. However, there is a lack of adoption of those methods. We argue that one of the primary reasons for this is the absence of proper feedback within security-sensitive situations. We believe that a graphical representation of security-related consequences can positively influence security-sensitive user decisions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capture the Flag With a Twist</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/ctf_with_twist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 11:51:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/ctf_with_twist/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Brecken Mumford
  Taylor students compete remotely in a computer hacking competition.
    Last Saturday, four Taylor teams competed remotely against other universities in a cybersecurity capture the flag competition hosted by Buena Vista University (BVU) in Storm Lake, Iowa.
The four Taylor teams met in Euler 218&amp;frasl;219 from 10:45 p.m. to 9 p.m. to commence the competition. They joined the other eight teams from across the United States via Google Hangouts to chat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved Kernel Security Through Memory Layout Randomization</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/projects/improved_kernel_security_through_memory_layout_randomization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 11:58:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/projects/improved_kernel_security_through_memory_layout_randomization/</guid>
      <description>Improved Kernel Security Through Memory Layout Randomization  Dannie M. Stanley Dongyan Xu Eugene H. Spafford Fri, Dec 6, 2013 
The vast majority of hosts on the Internet, including mobile clients, are running on one of three major operating system families. Malicious operating system kernel software, such as the code introduced by a kernel rootkit, is strongly dependent on the organization of the victim operating system. Due to the lack of diversity of operating systems, attackers can craft a single kernel exploit that has the potential to infect millions of hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSE Curriculum Info</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/information/curriculum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/information/curriculum/</guid>
      <description>Computer Science Learn about Computer Science  
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science 
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Bachelor of Science in Computer Science 
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Bachelor of Science in Computer Science with Systems Curriculum 
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Computer Science Minor 
 Computer Science Digital Media Learn about Computer Science - Digital Media  
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science - Digital Media 
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Bachelor of Science in Computer Science - Digital Media With Systems Curriculum</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact   Dr. Jon Denning, Department Co-chair
   General Contact Email: cseinfo@cse.taylor.edu
Phone: 765.998.5162
Want to Contact Faculty?
Want to Schedule a Visit?
Social Media            Facebook     Twitter     LinkedIn         Dr. Stefan Brandle, Department Co-chair
   For Prospective Employers Contact Lara Horsley - CSE Program Assistant</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filler</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/activities/filler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/activities/filler/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filler</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/courses/filler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/courses/filler/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>