<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>People on TU Computer Science and Engineering</title>
    <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/categories/people/</link>
    <description>Recent content in People on TU Computer Science and Engineering</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 12:52:15 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://timtheswan.github.io/categories/people/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Alumni</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/alumni/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 12:52:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/alumni/</guid>
      <description>Zach Alford   Zach Alford teaches math
    Zach Alford graduated from Taylor in 2016 with a Computer Science major, and Mathematics minor.
Zach appreciates how his Taylor education gave him skills integral to future development, both in his field and out. Academically, Zach learned attention for accuracy, cognitive persistence, how to work in groups, and valuable problem-solving skills. In Taylor&amp;rsquo;s liberal arts education, Zach learned how to effectively express himself, both in conversation and in writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Our Students</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/students/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 16:54:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/students/</guid>
      <description>Courtney Masters   Courtney is a Sophomore studying Digital Media
    Courtney Masters is a Sophomore studying Computer Science - Digital Media B.A. She is currently most interested in a career in web development or software engineering after she graduates in 2022.
Courtney heard about Taylor&amp;rsquo;s Computer Science department from her older brother and other friends. &amp;ldquo;I was particularly attracted to the digital media program because it incorporated design and film along with programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alumnus Receives Teaching Fellowship</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/alumnus_recieves_fellowship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 10:55:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/alumnus_recieves_fellowship/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Taylor Budzikowski
  Zach Alford (‘16) is one of the Woodrow Wilson Teaching Fellowship winners this year.
    Zach Alford (&amp;lsquo;16) received the Woodrow Wilson Teaching Fellowship earlier this year.
Alford is one of 24 recipients of the highly competitive fellowship in 2018. The fellowship selects educators who demonstrate impact and a strong background of STEM education in their undergraduate studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truax Creates Audio App for Amazon Alexa</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/truax_creates_audio_app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 10:41:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/truax_creates_audio_app/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Rayce Patterson
  The winners of GameJam Spring 2019
    Senior Caleb Truax III started the company Drift Sounds while still a student at Taylor University.
Truax is a film and computer science student who has worked on projects like the student short films, &amp;ldquo;The Summer of &amp;lsquo;59&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Nuworld,&amp;rdquo; according to his website. However, his entrepreneurial spirit led him and his business partner, Timothy Woten from technology company Sweetwater, to create Drift Sounds.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>