<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on TU Computer Science and Engineering</title>
    <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/categories/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on TU Computer Science and Engineering</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 08:18:38 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://timtheswan.github.io/categories/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Taylor Sends ThinSat to Space</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/thinsat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 08:18:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/thinsat/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Ellie Tiemens
  Computer science and engineering students made Taylor history with the launch of their nanosatellite. Photo by Ryan Jones
    Taylor University students and faculty recently partnered with NearSpace Launch Inc. to make history in sending nanosatellites to space.
On April 17 at 4:46 p.m., computer science students, engineering students and faculty watched as nearly two years their of hard work was launched into space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big dreams compete with little time at Game Jam 2019</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/gamejam_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 08:18:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/gamejam_2019/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Emily Pawlowski
  The winners of GameJam Spring 2019
    Twenty-four hours is not a lot of time. But for 20 students, it is just enough to create a video game.
Eight teams competed in the 2019 spring Game Jam. They had from April 4 - 6 to find out the theme, design the levels and program a working game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COS Students Make Physical Objects</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/cos_students_make/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 11:03:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/cos_students_make/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Carly Wheeler
  Senior Micah Stewart presents his project for COS 270.
    The Taylor University Computer Science Department is stepping into new territory this semester as students are able to take the class 3D rapid prototyping (COS 270) for the first time.
Taught by engineering project support Steve Dalcher, this pioneer class is diving into an area of computer programming brand new to Taylor academics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alumnus Receives Teaching Fellowship</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/alumnus_recieves_fellowship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 10:55:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/alumnus_recieves_fellowship/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Taylor Budzikowski
  Zach Alford (‘16) is one of the Woodrow Wilson Teaching Fellowship winners this year.
    Zach Alford (&amp;lsquo;16) received the Woodrow Wilson Teaching Fellowship earlier this year.
Alford is one of 24 recipients of the highly competitive fellowship in 2018. The fellowship selects educators who demonstrate impact and a strong background of STEM education in their undergraduate studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truax Creates Audio App for Amazon Alexa</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/truax_creates_audio_app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 10:41:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/truax_creates_audio_app/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Rayce Patterson
  The winners of GameJam Spring 2019
    Senior Caleb Truax III started the company Drift Sounds while still a student at Taylor University.
Truax is a film and computer science student who has worked on projects like the student short films, &amp;ldquo;The Summer of &amp;lsquo;59&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Nuworld,&amp;rdquo; according to his website. However, his entrepreneurial spirit led him and his business partner, Timothy Woten from technology company Sweetwater, to create Drift Sounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CERIAS Security Symposium</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/cerias_symposium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 15:00:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/cerias_symposium/</guid>
      <description>By: Dannie M. Stanley Sat, Apr 7, 2018 Ported from CyberSecurity Site
This week eight students ventured with me to Purdue University in West Lafayette, IN, to attend the 19th annual CERIAS Security Symposium. As a graduate student at Purdue I was heavily involved with CERIAS, so the trip was both highly relevant to our students and a good chance for me to reconnect with cybersecurity colleagues.
Symposium presenters and panelists are cybersecurity experts from academia, industry, and government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taylor Students Build Satellites</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/taylor_students_build_satellites/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 11:16:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/taylor_students_build_satellites/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Hannah Stumpf
  (L to R) Professor Bill Bauson stands with senior Justin Theien, chief engineer for the ThinSat satellite project.
    Taylor University students hope to launch a new ThinSat satellite in October 2018.
The group was first brought together by former Professor Emeritus of Engineering and Physics Hank Voss. Voss was involved in space science at a previous job, and it was there that he encountered a whole field of study called nanosatellites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lockheed Martin Grant Extended for Further Malware Research</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/lockheed_martin_grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 15:30:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/lockheed_martin_grant/</guid>
      <description>Reposted from Taylor University Site
    Aerospace and defense industry company Lockheed Martin has granted a $75,000 renewal of a grant to the Taylor University Computer Science (CSE) Department as part of a multi-year partnership to create cybersecurity solutions. The grant comes a little more than a year after the preliminary $100,000 grant from Lockheed Martin Advanced Technology Labs for research work done in 2017.
According to Taylor faculty members, a number of Taylor CSE students and faculty worked on the project during the 2017 spring and fall semesters, and also during the summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girls In STEM</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/girls_in_stem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 11:25:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/girls_in_stem/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Hannah Stumpf
  (Photograph provided by Unsplash)
    It all started with TWEET. And no, not the 280-character kind. TWEET stands for Taylor Women Engaging in Engineering and Technology, and those women of Taylor&amp;rsquo;s science, technology, engineering and math (STEM) created a program to get young girls in the community involved with science.
On Tuesday, March 6, one such meeting was held in Euler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity Lecture Asks Big Questions</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/cybersecurity_lecture_asks_big_questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 11:33:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/cybersecurity_lecture_asks_big_questions/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Hannah Stumpf
  The importance of the new cybersecurity major becomes a greater issue as world technology progresses.
    On Feb. 2, Taylor University welcomed Grant Hollis (&amp;lsquo;04), lead research scientist with Lockheed Martin Advanced Technology Laboratories (LM ATL), to speak on current events in cybersecurity and to raise awareness for Taylor&amp;rsquo;s new major.
Hollis worked part-time as a system administrator for Taylor&amp;rsquo;s computer science department.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Birth of Cybersecurity</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/birth-of-cybersecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 11:41:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/birth-of-cybersecurity/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Annabelle Blair
  A few students in the Software Reverse Engineering and Analysis class, pictured above, prepared for class by spending a day in Washington D.C..
    It&amp;rsquo;s been created and has a list of classes established, but Taylor&amp;rsquo;s cybersecurity major doesn&amp;rsquo;t officially exist-at least, not yet.
Current students will be allowed to enroll in the major when the catalogue comes out in August, and incoming students can declare it now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capture the Flag With a Twist</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/ctf_with_twist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 11:51:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/ctf_with_twist/</guid>
      <description>Ported from an Echo article by Brecken Mumford
  Taylor students compete remotely in a computer hacking competition.
    Last Saturday, four Taylor teams competed remotely against other universities in a cybersecurity capture the flag competition hosted by Buena Vista University (BVU) in Storm Lake, Iowa.
The four Taylor teams met in Euler 218&amp;frasl;219 from 10:45 p.m. to 9 p.m. to commence the competition. They joined the other eight teams from across the United States via Google Hangouts to chat.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>