<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on CSE</title>
    <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on CSE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 10:04:48 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet our Students</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/students/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 10:04:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/students/</guid>
      <description>Meet these Computer Science and Engineering students to see what they&#39;ve learned during their time at Taylor!   Caleb Dinsmore   CS Systems, Graduates May 2017
    Where are you from?
My dad is in the Marine Corps so I&amp;rsquo;ve moved around a lot. Most recently I lived in Murrieta, California.
&amp;nbsp;
Why did you choose Taylor? I had a friend who told me about Taylor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GameJam</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/gamejam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 15:00:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/gamejam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://gamejam.cse.taylor.edu/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TU CSE GameJam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  is a game jam series hosted every semester by the CSE Department and &lt;a href=&#34;https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/denning&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Jon Denning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and run by students at Taylor University. A game jam is a short, fun, and intense party during which students get together to develop a video game from scratch. Regardless of major or knowledge of programming, all TU students are invited to participate!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems Option</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:25:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/systems/</guid>
      <description>What is Systems? Systems is not a minor in Computer Science. The goal of the Systems curriculum is to help students recognize that the world is filled with systems (like educational, distribution, and manufacturing systems). It is the processes inhabiting these systems that produce value and help organizations achieve high performance. Our graduates are enjoying careers at enterprises of all sizes, including global consulting companies.
&amp;nbsp;   What in the world is Accenture selling?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abet Accreditation</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/abet_accreditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 11:07:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/abet_accreditation/</guid>
      <description>Our Engineering &amp;amp; Computer Engineering programs
are ABET-accredited.
   Accreditation The Engineering &amp;amp; Computer Engineering degree programs are accredited by the Engineering Accreditation Commission of ABET (https://www.abet.org). Program Educational Objectives  Prepare our graduates to server others dependably, most importantly their employer, customers, and community. Prepare our graduates to practice technical competence, producing reliable engineering designs. Prepare our graduates to exercise creativity in their work, fostering innovative solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/about_us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 10:18:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/about_us/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes alumni Ashley Crutcher designs websites that convince people to buy products,
like guacamole. But sometimes her goal is more serious, like convincing people to follow Jesus.
   At Taylor University, the Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering (CSE) department is more than just a section of the science building. We have our own community on the second floor of the environmentally sustainable Euler Science Complex that flourishes as a learning environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tweet</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/tweet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 17:03:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/tweet/</guid>
      <description>TWEET Meeting for Brunch
    Also known as Taylor Women Engaging in Engineering and Technology, this club allows women in Taylor’s science, technology, engineering, and math (STEM) to participate in fun activities together. They also work to promote STEM to young girls in the Upland community . TWEET’s mission is to provide a community that encourages and unites women in a field where they are are significantly outnumbered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CERIAS Security Symposium</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/cerias_symposium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 15:00:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/articles/cerias_symposium/</guid>
      <description>By: Dannie M. Stanley Sat, Apr 7, 2018
This week eight students ventured with me to Purdue University in West Lafayette, IN, to attend the 19th annual CERIAS Security Symposium. As a graduate student at Purdue I was heavily involved with CERIAS, so the trip was both highly relevant to our students and a good chance for me to reconnect with cybersecurity colleagues.
Symposium presenters and panelists are cybersecurity experts from academia, industry, and government.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>