<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Faculties on TU Computer Science and Engineering</title>
    <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Faculties on TU Computer Science and Engineering</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Jon Denning</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/denning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/denning/</guid>
      <description>Bio I started at Taylor in Fall 2014. I teach a broad set of courses, but my area of expertise is in computer graphics and algorithms. I find graphics fascinating because it creatively combines many disciplines—physics, math, data structures and algorithms, psychology, and art—and produces images that are simple, yet awe-inspiring and rich with details.
The past decade has been a whirlwind of excitement for and blessings on my family, and looking back it’s obvious that God has led us to where we are now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Stefan Brandle</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/brandle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/brandle/</guid>
      <description>Bio What do I say? Great literature is supposed to have a catchy first line. Moby Dick begins, “Call me Ishmael.” But I’m not sure that I’m up to great literature. And my name’s not Ishmael. Should I write something profound? Something frivolous? What does one say about oneself in this sort of situation?
I wish to serve God in all aspects of my life. That commission includes my professional field and my job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Art White</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/white/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:51:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/white/</guid>
      <description>Bio I teach because I believe the Lord has called me to teaching and I deeply enjoy teaching and time spent with young people. Seeing students become excited about the field of computing is extremely gratifying. I love experiencing the “aha!” moments as students comprehend new concepts in computer science. I enjoy working with students to help them develop their analysis, design, programming, and debugging skills. I find these skills apply not only to programming, but also to other areas of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Jonathan Geisler</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/geisler/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/geisler/</guid>
      <description>Bio What can I say that’s enlightening? I’m not as funny as Dr. Brandle, so I think I’ll just be plain and tell you a bit about myself.
I’m a Taylor Computer Science and Engineering grad (Dec. ’94), so I’ve been involved in the department since 1991. I took a couple years off to work at Argonne National Laboratory before attending Northwestern University for my PhD. Technically, I’m a Computer Engineer, so I work with the Physics department to make sure that program is up to snuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Tom Nurkkala</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/nurkkala/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/nurkkala/</guid>
      <description>Bio I’m at Taylor because I want to help train and mentor excellent computer scientists and engineers who are also dedicated followers of Christ. In addition, as a member of the Center for Missions Computing, I want to leverage the intellectual horsepower and spiritual maturity of the students at Taylor to help solve practical computing problems for the global mission community.
To accomplish these goals, I plan to employ my educational and industrial experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Dannie Stanley</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/stanley/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/stanley/</guid>
      <description>Bio When I set out to become a professor in 2004, I identified Taylor University specifically as the place that I would like to teach. I did not realize at the time how unlikely it was that I would actually get to work at my first choice (but here I sit). Though I was not a student at Taylor, I grew up in nearby Van Buren and was surrounded by community members involved with Taylor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Jeff Cramer</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/cramer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/cramer/</guid>
      <description>Bio As an elementary education major at Taylor University, I always thought I would someday like to be a professor. I never thought I would return to Taylor via the Computer Science and Engineering department!
After teaching in a public school in Indianapolis for six years, I decided to go back to graduate school. While working on my M.S. degree in Instructional Systems Technology at Indiana University, I realized how much I liked learning about the appropriate uses of technology in an educational setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Ben Roller</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/roller/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/roller/</guid>
      <description>Bio Stats Degrees:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mr. Tim Lehrian</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/lehrian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 14:13:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/lehrian/</guid>
      <description>Bio When I was a little kid, I told my dad I wanted to be an architect just like him. We would go into business together and call it “Lehrian &amp;amp; Father.” Only I didn’t pursue architecture. I did math instead.
My goal was not to work in IT as a career. Then IWU’s IT Dept snagged me shortly after graduation. That launched me into an IT career path that eventually resulted in working as a sysadmin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mr. William Slauson</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/slauson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 14:13:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/slauson/</guid>
      <description>Bio I was born into a family of soldiers, missionaries and physicians. I spent most of my life in a Northern Virginia suburb, but I have traveled extensively.My faith has played a central role in my life. I was saved young and have found purpose and joy in my relationship with Christ.
I have enjoyed technology since my first DOS machine at the age of 5. I also have broad interests in most of the liberal arts, but I especially enjoy mathematics, physics, philosophy and political science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mrs. Lara Horsley</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/horsley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 14:13:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/horsley/</guid>
      <description>Bio I’ve been working as the Program Assistant for the Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) department since fall 2011. For nine years I was the only sister of three older brothers, so I know how to handle anything these guys can throw at me. Prior to working for the CSE department, I worked on the first floor of Nussbaum Science Center as the Program Assistant for the School of Natural &amp;amp; Applied Sciences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Josh Hibschman</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/hibschman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/hibschman/</guid>
      <description>Bio Stats Degrees:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Steve Dalcher</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/dalcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/dalcher/</guid>
      <description>Bio I am a problem solver, technology is my problem solving toolset. I have always loved learning new things and widening the scope of issues that I can resolve. I teach students to do the same with several different technologies. For example, I teach students in COS 270, Rapid Prototyping, to make something using computer aided part 3D printing and laser cutting.
Stats Degrees:
 Ed.D, Adult and Community Education, 2015</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professor Darci Nurkkala</title>
      <link>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/nurkkala_darci/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timtheswan.github.io/faculty/nurkkala_darci/</guid>
      <description>Bio Stats Degrees:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>